muslima.com 2019-05-19

# Privacy Statement | Muslima.com

(Last updated 29 August 2018)

**1\. Preliminary**

**1.1 General**

Muslima.com (the "Website") is owned and operated by Cupid Media Pty Ltd ACN 104 844 564, an Australian registered company ("Cupid Media", "we", "our", "us").

Cupid Media is committed to protecting user privacy. We understand that visitors and users of the Website are concerned about their privacy, and the confidentiality and security of any Personal Data that is provided.

We will only collect, use and disclose Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy, the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), or the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (or other applicable law). If there is any inconsistency, the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (or other applicable law) will prevail to the extent of any inconsistency, except for users who are resident of a nation in the European Union, in which case the GDPR will prevail to the extent of any inconsistency.

**1.2 Contact**

Our contact details are:

**Online support form:** Click here (use this option for fastest service)

**Email:**[team@Muslima.com](mailto:team@Muslima.com)

**Telephone:** [+61 7 5571 1181](tel:+61 7 5571 1181)

**Fax Number:** [+61 7 3103 4000](tel:+61 7 3103 4000)

**Post:** Muslima.com, PO Box 9304, Gold Coast MC, QLD 9726, Australia

**Director:** Andrew Bolton

**Privacy Issues Email:**[privacy@cupidmedia.com](mailto:privacy@cupidmedia.com)

If You are based in the European Union, VeraSafe has been appointed as Cupid Media’s European Union representative for data protection matters. In addition to contacting us using our above contact information, VeraSafe can be contacted in regard to matters related to the processing of Your personal data. To make such an inquiry, please contact VeraSafe using this contact form: <https://www.verasafe.com/privacy-services/contact-article-27-representative>.

Alternatively, VeraSafe can be contacted at the following addresses:

**Name:** Matthew Joseph  
**Address:** Zahradníčkova, 1220/20A, Prague 15000, Czech Republic; or

**Name:** VeraSafe Ireland Ltd  
**Address:** Unit 3D North Point House, North Point Business Park, New Mallow Road, Cork T23AT2P, Ireland.

**1.3 Your consent**

This Privacy Policy sets out Cupid Media's policies relating to the collection and use of Your Personal Data whilst You use the Website and Cupid Media’s Related Websites. Words that are capitalized, such as "Personal Data" and "Special Category Personal Data", are defined in clause 7 of this policy.

By accessing and using the Website You are consenting to the collection and use of Your Personal Data in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. By registering an account or logging on as a member on the Website or a Related Website, You are consenting to the collection and use of Your Personal Data and Special Category Personal Data. 

You may withdraw Your consent to our collection and use of Your Personal Data at any time by ceasing to use the relevant Website or Related Website. If You are a member that has created an account, You may withdraw Your consent to our collection and use of Your Personal Data and Special Category Personal Data by ceasing to use Your account and making a request for Your account to be suspended or deleted. Requests for suspension or deletion can be made through Your account, or by contacting us using the contact information contained in clause 1.2 of this Policy. Please note that in order to erase any Personal Data or Special Category Personal Data that we have already collected from You, a request must be made using the process set out in clause 5.6 of this Privacy Policy.

**2\. Anonymity**

Due to the nature of the services provided by Cupid Media it is impractical for us to deal with You without knowing Your full name. When You register for our services You are required to use truthful and accurate information and You will not have the option to use a pseudonym.

**3\. Collection of data**

**3.1 All users**

Whenever users (including non-member users) visit the Website, our servers automatically record information for statistical purposes about Your usage of the Website such as:

**(a)** the type of browser used;  
**(b)** the referring URL;  
**(c)** the IP address;  
**(d)** the number and type of pages viewed;  
**(e)** the date and time of visits; and  
**(f)** the exit URL.  

This information we collect about You is not Personal Data and, in any event, remains anonymous. We do not link the anonymous information to any other Personal Data unless You have either registered as a member or logged on as a member at the time of use. Accordingly, if You have not identified Yourself on the Website, such as by registering as a member or logging on as a member, we will not link a record of Your usage of our Website to You personally.

**3.2 Members**

Upon Your registration as a member we collect information about You in order to provide You with the full benefits of membership. We collect non-identifying information as well as Personal Data from You directly when You first register, and also from time to time thereafter if You provide us with additional information.

Personal Data which may be collected by Cupid Media includes:

**(a)** Your full name;  
**(b)** Your email address;  
**(c)** Your residential address;  
**(d)** Your phone number;  
**(e)** A photograph of You;  
**(f)** Your age;  
**(g)** Your occupation;  
**(h)** A description of Your appearance;  
**(i)** Your credit card and billing information (if provided by You).

Information which we may also collect and which may be deemed as constituting Special Category Personal Data includes, without limitation:

**(a)** Your racial or ethnic origin;  
**(b)** Your political opinions;  
**(c)** Your religious beliefs or affiliations;  
**(d)** Your philosophical beliefs or trade union membership;  
**(e)** Your health;  
**(f)** Your sexual preferences, practices or orientation;  
**(g)** Your criminal record (if You are a resident of the USA).

By accessing and using the Website You are explicitly consenting to the collection and use of Your Special Category Personal Data in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

**3.3 Cookies and other tracking technologies**

To improve Your experience on our Website, we may use cookies and other tracking technologies, such as pixel tags, web beacons, device IDs, or advertising IDs.

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on Your browser, however please note that if You do this You may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.

Our website uses Cookies and other tracking technologies to support Google Analytics for:

**(a)** Google Marketing Platform integrations;  
**(b)** Demographic and Interest Reporting;  
**(c)** Display Advertising including Remarketing and Google Display Network Impression Reporting to advertise our services online;  
**(d)** Optimizing and personalizing ad services based on Your past visits to our Website;  
**(e)** Reporting the use of ad services and interactions with ad impressions and how they are related to visits to our site.

Our website uses Google Analytics, a service which transmits website traffic data to Google servers in the United States. Google Analytics does not identify individual users or associate Your IP address with any other data held by Google. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and web page usage.

You can customize or opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising using the Ads Settings for Your Google account.

Cookies and other tracking technologies may also be used to support analytics by other third parties.

**3.4 Third parties and social media**

We may allow third parties, including authorized service providers, advertising companies, data management platforms, and ad networks to serve advertisements on our sites. These companies may use tracking technologies (such as cookies, pixel tags, web beacons, device IDs, or advertising IDs) to collect information about users who view or interact with their advertisements. Any information that these third-parties collect via cookies is completely anonymous and is non-identifiable.

These third parties may include, but are not limited to: 360, Adobe, Akamai, Appnexus, Baidu, Bing, Cake, Criteo, Ecom Services, Eyeota, Facebook, Firebase, Google Ads, Google Ads Manager, Google Analytics, Index Exchange, Naver, Olark, Oracle, Publift, Pubmatic, Pusher, RayGun, Rubicon Project, SDL, Sentient, SnapChat, Taboola, Twitter, Urban Airship, Yahoo, Yandex, Zero Bounce.

You may refuse the use of third party data collection by selecting the appropriate settings on Your browser or by switching off Your profile.

There are a number of places on our Website where You may access third party websites that do not operate under this Privacy Policy and that we do not control. Such third party websites may collect Your information, including personal data. We recommend that You consult the privacy statements of all third party websites You visit.

Cupid Media also uses interfaces with social media sites such as Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Instagram, Pinterest, Weibo and others. If You choose to "like" or "share" information from this Website through these services, You should review the privacy policy of that service. If You are a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social media site to connect Your visits to this site with other Personal Data.

**3.5 Promotion to You**

In order to promote our products and services to You, we may provide a hash of Your email address (and no other Personal Data) to third parties, such as Facebook, in order to better target our advertising to You by using products such as Facebook's Custom Audiences.

A comparison of Your hashed email address will only be for the purpose of promoting our goods and services to You, and will not be used by that third party for any other purpose. The comparison of the hash of Your email address will not be used to identify You or Your email address, and no further information about You will be provided by us to that third party.

**4\. Purposes of collecting, holding, using and disclosing Personal Data**

**4.1 Collect from You only**

Where it is reasonable or practical to do so, we will endeavor to only collect Personal Data about You from You.

**4.2 Purposes of collecting Personal Data**

We will only collect Personal Data that is reasonably necessary for:

**(a)** enabling us to process Your application for membership and enabling us to provide services to You (including creating Your publicly viewable profile, allowing members to search for suitable members, and providing mechanisms for communication between members);  
**(b)** our internal research and statistical purposes (including market segmentation and customer value analysis);  
**(c)** enabling us to forward to You other information or material which we believe may be of interest to You;  
**(d)** enabling a payment processor to process the payment of subscription fees;  
**(e)** any other purpose specified in our Website Terms of Use

(the "Primary Purpose").

**4.3 Holding of Personal Data**

We will take reasonable steps to protect Personal Data that we hold from:

**(a)** misuse, interference and loss; and  
**(b)** unauthorized access, modification or disclosure.  

In the unlikely event that there is a serious data breach that is likely to result in a risk to Your rights and freedoms we shall, without undue delay, notify the appropriate supervisory authority. Where there is a high risk that a serious data breach will impact upon Your rights and freedoms, we will also notify You without undue delay of such a breach.

**4.4 Destruction of Personal Data**

We will keep Your information only for as long as we need it for legitimate business purposes and as permitted by applicable legal requirements. If:

**(a)** we hold Personal Data about You; and  
**(b)** we no longer need the Personal Data for any purpose for which the information may be processed or disclosed by us under this Policy, the GDPR or Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) or other applicable law; and  
**(c)** we are not required by or under a law of the European Union, an Australian law, this Policy, other applicable law, or a court/tribunal order, to retain the information,

we will take reasonable steps in the circumstances to erase the information or to ensure that the information is de-identified. If certain information has been provided to third parties in accordance with this Privacy Policy, retention of that information will be subject to the policies of the relevant third party.

**4.5 Use and disclosure of Personal Data**

We will only use or disclose Personal Data for the Primary Purpose where it is reasonably necessary. Use of Personal Data for the Primary Purpose will include the use of Personal Data in automated decision making processes.

We will only use or disclose Personal Data about You for a purpose other than the Primary Purpose (the "Secondary Purpose") where the following apply:

**(a)** the Secondary Purpose is related to the Primary Purpose and, if the Personal Data is Special Category Personal Data, the Secondary Purpose is directly related to the Primary Purpose; and  
**(b)** You would reasonably expect us to use or disclose the Personal Data for the Secondary Purpose; or  
**(c)** You have consented to the use or disclosure for the Secondary Purpose; or  
**(d)** the use or disclosure of the Personal Data is required or authorized under the GDPR, an Australian law, other applicable law or a court/tribunal order.

You may withdraw Your consent to our use of Your Personal Data for the Primary and Secondary Purposes at any time by contacting us using the contact information contained in clause 1.2 of this Policy. However, this may affect or limit Your ability to use the Website and Cupid Media's services.

**4.6 Disclosure to Third Party Country recipients and International Organizations**

Any profile information that You have provided to us will be publicly viewable on Your profile, irrespective of the location of the viewer. By creating a profile You acknowledge that overseas recipients will be able to view Your profile.

In order to provide customer support, perform back office functions, perform fraud prevention tasks, or provide services to You we may need to allow our staff or suppliers (who may be located or whose resources may be located other than Your country of residence) to access Your profile information, billing information or other Personal Data that You have supplied. 

We have implemented security measures to protect the security of Your Personal Data. However, as with any transfer of data, there are still risks of data breaches. There may be instances where Your Personal Data is transferred to Third Party Countries and International Organizations, which have not been the subject of an adequacy decision by the General Data Protection Regulation Commission. Such transfers are necessary in order for us to perform our obligations set out in the Cupid Media Website Terms of Use. 

By providing Your Personal Data and Special Category Personal Data You are explicitly consenting to the international transfer and processing of such data in accordance with this Policy, in full and informed knowledge of the risks associated with such transfers and processing. 

You may withdraw Your consent at any time by contacting us using the contact information contained in clause 1.2 of this Policy. However, this may affect or limit Your ability to use the Website and Cupid Media's services. 

In all other circumstances we will only disclose Personal Data to a Third Party Country recipient or International Organization if the disclosure of the information is required or authorized by or under a law of the EU, an Australian law, other applicable law or a court/tribunal order.

**4.7 Unsolicited information**

If we collect Personal Data which we have not sought or requested, and if we determine that we are otherwise permitted to collect that information in compliance with the GDPR, the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) or other applicable law, that information will be dealt with in accordance with the terms of this Policy. If, however, we determine that the collection of Your Personal Data is not permitted under the terms of the GDPR, the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) or other applicable law, then we will destroy or de-identify that information as soon as practicable, where it is lawful and reasonable to do so.

**4.8 Information not confidential**

Any material or information provided by You, save and except for any Personal Data (the use of which is governed by this Privacy Policy), will be treated as non-confidential and non-proprietary and we may use such material or information without restriction. Specifically, Cupid Media will use such material or information (including any profile information, photographs, video or audio recordings) that You have provided to us in order to copy Your profile into any other relevant dating site owned and operated by Cupid Media. Any such material or information provided by You will be made available for other members or users of the Website to read.

**4.9 Communication**

We reserve the right to send electronic mail to You regarding recommended matches, notification alerts of activity such as interest alerts or message alerts, promotions or offers, changes or additions to our services, or any products and services of our affiliated businesses. Where You are a member You may manage Your email preferences by using the settings on the “Notifications” page to customize what type of email communications You wish to receive.

**5\. Access, correction and portability**

**5.1 Access to Personal Data**

We will provide You with access upon request to the Personal Data held by us in relation to You except to the extent that:

**(a)** giving access would be unlawful; or  
**(b)** denying access is required or authorized by or under a law of the European Union, an Australian law, other applicable law or a court/tribunal order.

**5.2 Requests for access**

To request access to the Personal Data held by us about You, You must contact us using the contact details provided in clause 1.2. Following Your request we will contact You within a reasonable time and by no later than within one (1) month from the date of receipt of Your request. We will either provide You with the requested Personal Data or notify You when we will provide You with the Personal Data. In any event, the Personal Data requested will be provided within one month of our receipt of Your request, unless we decide not to provide You with access to the Personal Data. Where we have decided not to provide You with access to the Personal Data, we will advise You of the reasons for our decision.

**5.3 Data portability**

Insofar as it does not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others and where You have communicated a request to us using the contact information in clause 1.2:

**(a)** where we have employed an automated means to process Your Personal Data after receiving Your written request, we will provide You with such Personal Data that we have collected in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format.  
**(b)** after receiving Your request, where technically feasible, we will transmit Your personal data directly to another data holder.

**5.4 Commercially sensitive information**

Where providing You access to Your Personal Data would reveal evaluative information generated by us in connection with a commercially sensitive decision-making process we will give You an explanation for the commercially sensitive decision rather than direct access to the Personal Data.

**5.5 Use of intermediaries**

Where we are not required to provide You with access to the Personal Data then we will, if it is reasonable to do so, give consideration to whether the use of mutually agreed intermediaries would allow sufficient access to meet our respective needs.

**5.6 Correction and erasure of Personal Data**

It is Your responsibility to ensure that the information You provide to us is accurate and to update Your Personal Data as necessary.

If for any reason You are unable to correct any Personal Data held by us, please contact us using the contact details provided in clause 1.2 and we will take reasonable steps to correct Your Personal Data.

If we elect not to correct Your information, we will notify You within one month of the reason of our refusal and the mechanisms available to You to object to our refusal.

If we correct or erase Personal Data about You that we previously disclosed to another entity we will take reasonable steps in the circumstances to give that notification, unless it is impracticable or unlawful to do so.

If You wish to have Your Personal Data erased, please communicate Your request to us using the contact information provided in clause 1.2. The only circumstances in which we will not take reasonable steps to erase Your Personal Data are where we need to keep it in accordance with another provision of this Privacy Policy, the GDPR, or for any other legal reason. However, our deleting of Your Personal Data will also result in the deletion of Your Cupid Media account and will mean You are unable to access our services.

**5.7 Refusal to correct or erase**

If at any time we refuse or deny You access to Your Personal Data, or refuse to correct or erase Your Personal Data, we will provide You with reasons for such denial or refusal.

**5.8 Restriction of processing**

You may request that we limit or restrict the manner in which we deal with and process Your Personal Data. Where we are satisfied grounds for restriction exist, we will only process Your Personal Data: with Your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims against Us; or for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person.

**5.9 Costs**

Access to, erasure and rectification of Your Personal Data, including any communications related thereto, will generally be provided free of charge. Where Your requests are manifestly unfounded or excessive in nature (particularly due to repetitiveness) we may elect to charge You a reasonable fee taking into account the administrative costs of providing the information or communication, or taking the action requested. Where Your requests are manifestly unfounded or excessive in nature we may also refuse Your request.

**5.10 Specific objection rights**

If it becomes necessary for us to process Your Personal Data without Your consent for reasons of:

**(a)** performing a task in the public interest;  
**(b)** the exercise of an official authority that has been vested in us; or  
**(c)** where it is in our legitimate interests or the legitimate interests of a third party to do so;

You will have the right to object to such use.

If You object to certain uses of Your Personal Data, we will refrain from processing Your Personal Data unless compelling legitimate grounds exist for the processing which otherwise override Your interests, rights and freedoms, or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

If we have collected Your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy and elect to use such Personal Data for the purposes of direct marketing (to which You consent), You have the right to object at any time to such processing. Upon receiving an objection we will, as soon as is reasonably practical, cease using Your Personal Data for the purposes of direct marketing.

**6\. Complaints**

**6.1 Making a complaint**

If You believe that we have used or disclosed Your Personal Data in a manner which is contrary to this Policy or otherwise breaches an applicable law, then You should email us at [privacy@cupidmedia.com](mailto:privacy@cupidmedia.com). If You are based in the European Union and have a complaint regarding Your Personal Data, You may also contact our European representative VeraSafe using the contact information contained in clause 1.2 of this Privacy Policy.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the relevant supervisory authority in Your jurisdiction. If You are unsure who Your relevant supervisory authority may be, please contact us so that we may provide You with assistance.

**6.2 Our response**

Within 30 days of receipt of Your complaint we will notify You in writing as to what action we propose to take in relation to Your complaint and will provide You with details of what further action You can take if You are not satisfied with our response.

**7\. Definitions**

**"Collection"** means the acquisition of Your Personal Data.

**"General Data Protection Regulation"** and **"GDPR"** mean Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of The European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC.

**"International Organization"** means an organization and its subordinate bodies governed by public international law, or any other body which is set up by, or on the basis of, an agreement between two or more countries.

**"Third Party Country"** means a country that is not a member of the European Union.

**"Personal Data"** means any information relating to an identifiable natural person ('data subject'); an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person and includes Special Category Personal Data.

**"Processing"** means any operation or set of operations which is performed on personal data or on sets of personal data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction.

**"Purposes"** means the Primary and Secondary purposes.

**"Special Category Personal Data"** means personal data revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, Your criminal record, genetic and biometric data for the purpose of uniquely identifying a natural person, data concerning health or data concerning Your sex life or sexual orientation.

**"Third Party"** means a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or body other than the data subject, controller, processor and persons who, under the direct authority of the controller or processor, are authorized to process personal data.

**"Related Website"** means any other website owned, operated or controlled by Cupid Media Pty Ltd ACN 104 844 564.

**"You"** means the individual about whom we are collecting Information.
